IT BUSINESS SYSTEMS ANALYST (CONTRACT POSITION) Summary

Experienced Business Analyst with the technical expertise and business acumen necessary to translate business requirements and objectives into scalable, highly resilient and successful system solution. A dedicated and resourceful employee with an aptitude for achieving success in projects of varying complexities. Versed in resource logistics and quality assurance in both corporate and government sectors. A captivating communicator with excellent written and oral communication skills.

Highlights

- Business systems analysis
- Project management
- Requirements gathering
- Customer relations specialist
 Detail-oriented
- Project tracking
- Scrum methodology
- Natural leader
- Quality assurance and control
- Troubleshooting
- Interviewing expertise
- Staffing and recruiting professional

Experience

04/2014

IT Business Systems Analyst (Contract Position) Accenture Contractor Jobs il/4 Great Valley, NY

- Analyze business process and practices in an effort to focus the design and implementation of information technology solutions to meet customer needs.
- Collaborate with Programmers/Analyst on and on-going basis.
- Apply analytical skills within functional area.
- Support SharePoint users within the company by addressing any reported issues which cannot be resolved by Information Management Service Center.
- Build sites and sub-sites.
- Troubleshoot SharePoint issues that arise (content, user access, document libraries, list, moving sites, workflows, etc).
- Test software upgrades in both QA and Production environment.
- Manage and troubleshooting user permissions, responding to incoming user request.
- · Work on complex functionality such as working with business end users to assist in the creation of workflows, creation of new sites, removal of sites, etc.
- Test new patches that are installed in the application.
- Conducted interviews with key business users to collect information on business processes and user requirements.
- Assessed the impact of current business processes on users and stakeholders.
- Mapped current processes and offered recommendations for improvement.
- SharePoint development with InfoPath, SharePoint Designer and HTML creating custom lists, libraries, workflows, forms and look and feel.
- Creating custom Page Layouts & Content Types in SPD
- Training end users on lists, libraries, pages, publishing, web parts, importing, exporting, navigation and many other features

10/2010 to 04/2014

Business Analyst/ SharePoint Administrator Kepro il/4 Concord, NH

- Provided support for the Defense Travel Systems (DTS) as a Defense Travel Administrator (DTA) for over 17,000 civilian and military personnel that belong to the NAVAIR/NAWCAD organization.
- Served as DTS system administrator responsible for assisting with account login/creation, as well as amendment/cancellation of documents such as travel authorizations, and vouchers.
- Worked directly with SATO to ensure reservations were processed accurately.
- Performed research on the JTR/JFTR to provide current information to customers and teammates.
- Monitored and maintained the National Travel Support team database.
- Processed new travelers through self registration.
- Managed approver and traveler profiles.
- Manually entering and tracking travel expenses in NAVY ERP.
- Researching any financial issue associated with travel and the DTS system.
- Performed complex general accounting functions, including preparation of journal entries, account analysis and balance sheet reconciliations.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to draft project schedules and plans.
- Monitored team progress and enforced deadlines.

07/2008 to 07/2009

Systems Analyst MIL Corporation i1/4 City, STATE

- Provided support for the Defense Travel Systems (DTS) as a Defense Travel Administrator (DTA) for over 17,000 civilian and military personnel that belong to the NAVAIR/NAWCAD organization.
- Served as DTS administrator responsible for assisting with account login/creation, as well as amendment/cancellation of documents such as travel authorizations, and vouchers.
- Worked directly with SATO to ensure reservations were processed accurately.

- Performed research on the JTR/JFTR to provide current information to customers and teammates.
- Monitored and maintained the National Travel Support team database.
- Processed new travelers through self registration.
- Managed approver and traveler profiles.
- Manually entering and tracking travel expenses in NAVY ERP.
- Researching any financial issue associated with travel and the DTS system.
- Coordinated verification and review of Government Travel Orders.
- Ensured military and civilians adhered to the JTR/JFTR guidelines.
- Utilized DTS and HEAT systems to process Central Travel Team requests.

01/2006 to 07/2006

Administrative Assistant ITT Industries i1/4 City, STATE

- Performed a various administrative and security functions.
- Maintained customer account databases.
- Verified visitor security clearances and access processing.
- Scheduled meeting appointments and changes via the central calendar system.
- Managed purchase orders, and office correspondence.
- Assisted in answering telephone switch board calls and greeting visitors to the office.

Education

2016

Master of Science: Project Management University of Maryland i1/4 City, State

2013

Bachelor of Arts: Business Management Western Governors University i1/4 City, State

Skills

Systems and Software:

Joint Personnel Adjudication System (JPAS), Navy ERP, BASIC, HEAT, Defense Travel System (DTS), Aircraft and Personnel Automated Clearance System (APACS), Windows, MAC OSX, SharePoint 2007 and 2010, 2010 SharePoint Designer, DOD Emalls, Microsoft Office Suite, Gmail, Teamwork, Adobe Suites

Training

•SharePoint 2010 Power User 06/2012

•Building Application and Workflows with SharePoint Designer 2010: Hands On 08/2012

•Developing InfoPath forms for SharePoint: Hands On 09/2012

•SharePoint for Project Management 08/2012